

1 The Pointe, 9 Mellor Road, Cheadle Hulme, SK8 5AT 07961 804540 | callummccleandev@gmail.com

INTRODUCTION

Full Stack Developer experienced in agile methodologies as well as continuous integration and continuous delivery techniques. Skilled in AWS cloud services and serverless development methods. Uses technical skills to deliver high standard systems and documentation. Consistently hits targets and deadlines, always excited to learn new skills and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Ditto AT

Software Developer | March 2018 - Present

- Responsible for the agile Kanban process including stand ups, Jira board management, Jenkins continuous integration and continuous delivery along with general project management.
- Working on a greenfield SaaS project with an AWS based scalable micro-service architecture. Using a serverless, infrastructure as code approach.
- Technologies include React, Typescript, NodeJS, C#, GraphQL, MySQL, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Appsync, AWS S3, AWS Cloudfront.
- Strong communication with product owners and stakeholders to clarify and validate requirements before developments is started.

Healthcare Communications UK

Graduate Software Developer | August 2017 - March 2018

- Responsible for implementing new features and bug fixes on a large C# (MVC) web project. This
 includes everything from writing stored procedures in SQL, back end business logic to front end UI
 and client side scripts.
- Provide 3rd line support to other areas of the business and customers. Including investigation and confirming suspected issues and writing bespoke SQL queries to gather needed data.
- Part of a fast-moving agile team that complete fortnightly sprints and deliver new releases on a monthly basis.

Newcastle University

Research Assistant | Summer 2017 (Full Time)

- Responsible for research in to and the creation of a bespoke program for the generation and injection of synthetic users in to a monitored Twitter stream.
- Creation of a supervised classification model that can accurately predict the class of an unseen tweet (within the context of the Zika virus in Brazil) in to one of three possibilities.

• Continuation of research conducted for final year dissertation, entitled: From Twitter Analytics to User Engagement: a case study on Zika epidemics in Brazil.

EDUCATION

Newcastle University | 2014 – 2017 | Bachelor of Science

Computing Science 1st Class Honours (77%)

Falibroome Academy | 2012 - 2014 | A-Levels

Sociology A
Geography B
ICT B

TECHNICAL SKILLS

| React | AWS | Git |
|------------|---------|----------|
| TypeScript | C# .NET | Jenkins |
| Javascript | SQL | Java |
| GraphQL | NoSQL | TDD |
| Node.js | Jira | HTML/CSS |

ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

- Second Author on the research paper entitled 'Recruiting from the network: discovering Twitter users
 who can help combat Zika epidemics'. The paper was presented at and published by The
 International Conference for Web Engineering 2017 in Rome (ICWE).
- University funded trip to work with research colleagues at PUC Rio University, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.
 A great learning experience to work within a fully functioning and renowned research group as a team member.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.